[theme music playing]
[Ivy] Mom, are you here?
-[Camia screaming]
-[dishes break]
Mom!
Mom?
Mom…
Can't you remember me? Or anything?
What did they do to you, Mom?
What happened to you?
[Raul] Love?
Is there something you want to tell me?
[Diego] I'm sure of it. That girl is Lily.
If they don't want to tell me,
then I'll look into it myself.
-Leave your pit and face me!
-Fine, I will.
But I'm not a coward
because I'm not afraid of you.
Tonight, all your lies
will come to an end.
[Ivy] We have to leave before
that bastard returns.
-He's kind! He's kind!
-We should leave.
He is not kind! He's the reason
we became like this!
Why our family fell apart! He is not kind!
I won't let you hurt Grandpa again!
I already know everything. They told me.
I know what you traitors did!
You are going to resign as
governor of Poblacion Ardiente.
You can't do this, Papa.
You cannot do this!
Kill Raul, and you can keep
your governorship.
I will expose this family's
dirtiest secrets!
[scoffs] Go! Go ahead, Raul.
Give me one good reason
to finally get rid of you!
I will kill you.
Get this trash out of here!
-[Raul] Emilia!
-[Emilia] Please stop!
-[Raul] Let go!
-[Emilia] Raul…
-[Raul] I can't stay here!
-[Emilia] Just go with them.
[somber music playing]
[door rattles]
[thumping]
[suspenseful music playing]
[music fading]
Aunt Claire, what are we going to do?
I'm running out of options already.
We will fight Julio head-on.
How?!
I will talk to some of my lawyer friends.
I'm sure they'll find
a loophole in his plans.
Are they ready to die?
Because I'm sure they'll
be Papa's future targets.
Raul, would you mind?
You're just standing there!
Help us solve this problem!
You know what?
Do whatever the hell you want.
I don't give a crap.
All I know is I have to get out of here.
How dare you, Raul?!
I chose you over being a governor,
and this is what you're gonna do to me?
How dare you!
I should've done this a long time ago.
I should've left you way back!
So, if you'll excuse me, I have to leave.
Don't you dare.
-Hold on.
-Sir, you can't.
[Emilia] Come on, try it.
[bodyguard] Sir, please. You can't leave.
Emilia, come on! Why are you doing this?
[grunts] Ouch!
[grunting]
-Emilia, won't you stop them?
-[Emilia] No.
Raul has to realize that I'm
the only one he's got left.
[groans]
[suspenseful music playing]
[instrumental theme music playing]
[sighs]
You haven't changed, Mom.
You're still beautiful.
When I was a kid, Mom, I told myself…
I wish…
I'd be as beautiful as my mother.
I remember our life back then, Mom.
We didn't have much, but we were so happy.
[sighs]
Mom, when I was a kid…
do you know…
what I really love that
you and Dad would always do?
It was during bedtime…
when you and Dad would read
to me The Count of Monte Cristo.
That was my favorite book, Mom.
I never imagined that…
what happened in the book…
would…
would also happen to us?
To our family.
Thirteen years…
[instrumental theme music
continues playing]
I longed for you.
And now, Mom?
I'm with you again.
But it hurts…
[sniffles]
It hurts because you can't remember me.
It hurts because
you don't know me as Lily.
You don't see me as your daughter.
[sniffles]
But I won't give up, Mom.
I'll do everything…
Everything I can to help you
regain your memories.
["Wildflower" by Arnel Pineda playing]
So you can recognize me again.
I promise, Mom.
["Wildflower" by Arnel Pineda
continues playing]
[voice breaking] I love you, Mom.
[song fading]
Nanny, Uncle…
I'll do everything to find out the truth.
Diego, isn't it too dangerous?
What if they won't let you in
at Miss Ivy's office in Manila?
I'll find a way.
Take care, Diego.
You're getting in too deep.
Don't worry about me. I know my limits.
I just want answers to my questions.
So I can freely love Ivy… or Lily.
I'll get going now, Nanny, Uncle.
-Take care!
-Be safe.
[car engine starts]
[sizzling]
[ominous music playing]
Mom.
Good thing you're awake now.
Uh…
I'm just cooking fried rice.
You used to cook this for me and Dad.
Fried rice, corned beef, and eggs.
Then we'd eat breakfast together.
After breakfast, we'd leave
the house together too.
Dad would go to his office,
while you and I would head off to school.
[Camia] I'm Camia Cruz.
[teacher] You teach Social Studies, right?
Good afternoon, sir. I'm Camia Cruz.
I tutor Diego.
I said take your hands off me!
Don't touch me!
[tense music playing]
Mom?
Mom, does your head hurt again?
[breathing heavily]
Here.
[water pouring]
Drink this, Mom.
-[glass breaks]
-[grunts]
[Ivy groaning]
I'm okay, Mom.
Move away, you might get hurt too.
Come here.
[instrumental theme music playing]
Sit down.
Wait a sec.
[instrumental theme music playing]
[Carlotta] Okay, I'll tell her
when she comes back,
but call me if she drops
by the office, okay?
-Yes, Miss Carlotta.
-Okay.
I'll go now. Thank you.
-Ma'am?
-Yes?
Where's Ivy? I need to see her.
Good morning, Mayor.
She left this morning.
Where did she go?
I assume she didn't go
to her office in Manila
because her assistant is here.
[nervous chuckle]
Joan got here after she left.
Is that true?
-Uh, yes, sir.
-Okay, call her now.
-Ah…
-Come on, hurry up!
[voice prompt] The subscriber
cannot be reached.
Please try again later.
[Arnaldo] Out of reach?
I've been trying to contact her
since last night.
Tell me where she went. Out with it.
Mayor, I already answered you.
And I think you need to leave.
[voice shaking] You're trespassing.
Trespassing?
But I'm the mayor here.
I know, sir.
But that's exactly why you have to leave.
I don't want to file a complaint.
[chuckles sarcastically]
[Arnaldo] She'll file a complaint.
Did you hear that?
[sighs]
Carlotta, I know Ivy's hiding
something from me.
And I swear, I'll find out what it is.
[tense music playing]
[sighs heavily]
[inhales sharply, groans]
Does it hurt?
[soft music playing]
[water pouring]
Hang on.
[soft music playing]
[sniffles]
Why?
I just missed…
how you used to take care of me.
[Ivy sniffles]
[soft music playing]
Let's eat.
Okay, Mom.
Take a seat, Mom.
Thank you.
[soft music playing]
[foreboding music playing]
Excuse me, sir?
Uh… Good afternoon, miss.
Is this the Aguas Building?
How can I help you, sir?
I'm looking for Aguas Realty Department.
Do you have an appointment, sir?
Uh, no.
But I just want to inquire
about the properties for sale.
We can only entertain
walk-in clients
through our marketing team.
The stairs are to my left.
You can inquire downstairs.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome, sir.
Mom, you should eat some more.
You only had a little.
Are you full?
All right, just drink this water.
Come with me.
Where to, Mom?
Mom?
You should sleep.
Oh, no, I can't.
Raul might come back. I can't sleep.
You're tired. You should rest.
-Mom, I'm okay.
-Lie down.
But Mom…
Mom--
Go to sleep.
[instrumental theme music playing]
Thank you, Mom.
["Wildflower" by Arnel Pineda playing]
♪ Let her cry, for she's a lady ♪
♪ Let her dream ♪
♪ For she's a child ♪
♪ She's a child ♪
♪ Let the rain fall down ♪
♪ Upon her ♪
♪ She's a free and gentle flower ♪
♪ Growing wild ♪
♪ Let her cry, for she's a lady ♪
♪ Let her dream ♪
♪ She's a child ♪
[song fading]
[sighs heavily]
[tense music playing]
Dad, we need to talk.
Be honest. What's going on
between you and Ivy?
Nothing.
Then why did you both disappear
during my party?
You too, Arnaldo?
Didn't we talk about this--
I won't stop until you tell me
where you took Ivy.
She's missing!
I don't know what you're
talking about, Arnaldo.
You don't? Dad, you can't deny
what kind of man you are.
Did you kidnap her so you
could get back at Grandpa?
So he won't touch you
after what you did to him?
Don't test my patience, Arnaldo!
And just so you know,
your grandfather is just using that woman.
Right now, she's useful to him.
But sooner or later,
he'll get rid of her too.
Just like you.
That's how your grandfather
sees you and your mom!
That's how wicked and selfish
your grandfather is!
Wicked?
Tough words from someone
who isn't a saint, Dad.
Ever since I can remember, Grandpa has
been more like a father to me than you.
[tense music playing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[no audio]
I like that smile, Emilia.
So, are you going with my suggestion
to challenge Julio head-on?
You said it yourself, Aunt Claire.
I can't go down without a fight.
[Claire] Humiliate Julio
in front of the media
and the public.
Show them the monster he really is.
[sinister music playing]
[exhales]
Good day, Governor. This way, please.
[Emilia] Hi. Hello there. Hi! Hello.
Hi.
Governor, this way, please.
Good afternoon. Good afternoon.
-Thank you for coming.
-[woman] Congressman!
My dad is here.
-Good day, sir.
-[Julio] Good day.
[man] How are you?
[Julio] How are you? Sit down, please.
Hello.
Hi.
Raul, Claire, please join us.
Come on.
-[woman] This way, please.
-[Julio] Thank you, dear.
You're welcome, sir.
-Pa.
-Hello, Emilia.
[tense music playing]
-[reporter 1] Hello, sir.
-Hello. Good day to you all.
[reporter 2] Thank you, sir,
for gracing us today.
[Julio] We should be the ones
thanking you.
Please, sit down. Sit down.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Please.
First of all,
to our friends from the press,
thank you very much for coming.
To my beloved children
of Poblacion Ardiente,
with a warm smile, your Señor Julio,
together with the rest
of the Ardiente Family,
wishes to formally thank you,
for your support and prayers
for my recovery.
However, it's only fair that
with public service…
comes fatigue and stress.
To be honest, I really want
to be genuinely happy…
but I just can't.
Because there's another crisis…
threatening the Ardiente family.
And as your humble servants…
we feel that we should let you know…
[camera shutter clicks]
that my daughter, Emilia…
[Julio sniffles]
She has been diagnosed
with ovarian cancer, stage 2.
[no audible dialogue]
[camera shutter clicks]
Our family has already
discussed the matter.
Emilia's health
is of the utmost importance.
So, today, there is something
she would like to announce.
Hello, friends. [chuckles nervously]
[Emilia] Ah…
You know how much I love you all.
Especially my constituents.
But we all face challenges
at some point in our lives.
And right now, I am dealing
with a health crisis…
as my father has just mentioned.
And because of this…
I would need to step down as
the governor of this province.
But please don't worry.
Because you know me, I'm a fighter.
I'll fight this disease.
So, when I come back,
I can serve you all once again.
As a stronger and firmer leader
than before.
So thank you very much.
Your friend Emilia
loves you all very much.
I love you all. I love you.
Thank you so much.
-[camera shutter clicks]
-[applauding]
Moving forward…
we know that a lot of people
depend on the governor.
So, the provincial council
has agreed that,
in order for us to continue
our service to the public,
the vice governor
will assume the vacant post.
Please call the vice governor.
Ladies and gentlemen of the press,
my beloved children of Poblacion Ardiente,
your Señor Julio would like to introduce
one of his dearest friends in politics,
Governor Emilia's successor,
Governor William Alvarez!
[all applauding]
-Auntie, let's go?
-Okay.
-We'll go ahead, Papa.
-[Emilia] Bye, Governor.
-Okay, Emilia. Take care.
-Emilia.
-Bye, Governor.
Claire. Raul. Have a safe trip.
Well…
Here's to you, Governor.
-Thank you, Congressman.
-[glasses clink]
[Julio] Mayor, join us.
You know, Arnaldo, our new
governor is a very good soldier.
Reliable and loyal.
Isn't that right, Alvarez?
You can count on me, Congressman.
When the time comes that
you step into my shoes,
you'd want to be surrounded by
the likes of Governor Alvarez.
I'll remember that, Grandpa.
Well then, it seems
we are all in agreement.
Viva Ardiente.
-Viva Ardiente.
[glasses clink]
Please excuse me for a while.
[tense music playing]
[William] What's our agenda for today?
-Thank you.
-Sure, Governor.
Excuse me, Congressman. I have to go.
[Julio] Governor.
Thank you very much for this
wonderful press conference.
Thank you very much
for accepting the position.
My honor and my pleasure.
[Julio] Okay.
-Arnaldo.
-Governor.
I'll be seeing you.
You will.
Take care, Governor.
You too, Congressman.
[tense music playing]
[Julio] I gathered you all here
because I have an important task for you.
I want you to take all the
belongings of Emilia and Raul…
and move them to the old
guesthouse behind the house.
Don't forget to move
Claire's belongings too.
Now, if Emilia complains,
tell me immediately.
I'll be the one to deal with her
accordingly.
Is that clear?
[all] Yes, Congressman.
Good, you may all leave now.
[sighs] Grandpa…
Isn't that too much?
I mean, you already got what you wanted.
Mom stepped down from office.
A little mercy?
[scoffs]
You know, Arnaldo, you don't understand.
Your mom has to learn a lesson.
And tapping her on the hand isn't enough.
You need to cripple her for her to learn.
Don't worry. Leave your mom to me.
Leave this matter to me. Mark my words.
The day will come when your
mother will thank me for this.
[clicks tongue]
In the meantime, I want you
to keep an eye on Miss Aguas.
Find out where that woman went.
Yes, Grandpa.
[woman] Have a seat.
[Diego] Thank you, ma'am.
What's this interview for exactly?
For a magazine feature
on Miss Ivy Aguas, ma'am.
Hold on.
[woman] Ivy?
You mean the daughter
of Mrs. Prianka Aguas?
Of course, I know her very well.
She was a transferee,
but we don't have any records
of her from her previous school.
What do you want to know about Ivy?
How was she as a student?
A quiet one.
She seldom talked to others.
At times, she would just
stare off into space,
especially during her first year here.
According to Mrs. Aguas,
Ivy went through a lot.
What do you mean, ma'am?
It had something to do with her
childhood and her real mom.
Apparently, it was something terrible.
Hold on… Her real mom?
Yes. Ivy is Mrs. Aguas' adopted daughter.
But despite how hard it was for her,
she was able to overcome it.
She turned out to be a bright,
diligent, and kind student.
No wonder Mrs. Aguas loved
and treated Ivy as her own.
She graduated at the top of her class,
both in grade school and high school.
In fact, she's one of the most
outstanding students
this school has produced.
Would you like to see our Hall of Fame?
You'll see Ivy's pictures
and achievements there.
[tense music playing]
[Emilia sniffles]
Pull yourself together, Emilia.
You can't be like this!
Auntie, I can't be anyone
or anything anymore!
I'm nobody! I am nobody, Aunt Claire.
Papa took away everything from me.
He already found someone
to replace me as governor.
Someone more capable and smarter.
I don't know!
[sobbing]
[sighs] Emilia…
You know, Aunt Claire,
sometimes, I wonder…
Does Papa love me at all?
[Emilia sniffles]
Emilia, that's enough.
[Claire] You've had enough!
What are you all doing here?
Hey! What's this about?
What are you doing here?
Ma'am, Congressman ordered us
to transfer your things
because you'll be moving
to the old guesthouse.
No, no! Wait! Wait!
Don't you dare touch my stuff!
-Hey, wait!
-Wait!
Stay away from me!
What are you doing?!
Those are mine! Don't touch those!
Wait! Those are my clothes! Give me that!
-We're sorry, ma'am.
-Give it to me!
-It's the congressman's orders.
-Don't you dare touch me!
Don't you dare touch me!
Hold on! Wait!
-Those are my clothes!
-We're sorry, ma'am.
We're just following orders.
[Emilia] Those are mine!
Hey! That's expensive!
-Give me that!
-We're really sorry, ma'am.
Sorry?! What sorry?! You can't do this!
This is not happening!
[sobbing]
Aunt Claire…
[mouthing silently]
[crying]
[sighs heavily]
Are you okay? Why do you look nervous?
I'm just excited to know more
about Miss Aguas.
Is this it?
I'm sorry.
My eyes aren't as good as they used to be.
So, I can't recognize all the photos here.
It's okay, ma'am.
[tense music playing]
[suspenseful sting]
Is this Ivy?
Yes, that's her.
[suspenseful music playing]
I have to go now.
Thank you, ma'am.
[suspenseful music playing]
[camera shutter clicks]
[Jepoy] You were right to call
your dad out, Mayor.
I know I'm not in the position to talk,
but in my one year of working here,
I've seen that it's only Governor Emilia
and Congressman Julio
who really love you.
But I feel sorry for Governor Emilia
considering what Sir Raul
was doing to her.
If I were in your shoes, Mayor,
if I were his son, I don't know
what I would have done to him.
He's a pathetic bastard.
And a worthless father.
I just thought, Mayor…
if Sir Raul could hurt your grandfather…
how much more your mother?
What do you mean?
You need someone to protect
Governor Emilia from Sir Raul.
Mayor…
I volunteer myself to be
your mom's personal bodyguard.
All right.
But not just Mama's bodyguard.
I also want you to watch over my dad.
I want to know everything he does.
As you wish, Mayor.
[sighs]
[somber music playing]
Miss! Miss, wait!
-Yes?
-[stuttering] For you.
-I'm Diego.
-Ivy Aguas.
Miss Aguas.
How will you benefit
from investing in Ardiente?
[woman] According to Mrs. Aguas,
Ivy went through a lot.
It had something to do with
her childhood and her real mom.
-Her real mom?
-Yes.
Ivy is Mrs. Aguas' adopted daughter.
-Is this Ivy?
-Yes, that's her.
[young Diego] What? Your family's leaving?
If I leave, who's going to be your friend?
No one will make me happy anymore.
And if you leave, I'll be lonely again.
I'll miss you.
Lily, why did you have to lie to us?
Why did you come back to Ardiente?
And what suffering did you go through?
What happened to your mom?
I'll ask you all about this
when I see you.
I hope you'll finally tell me the truth.
[somber music playing]
[groans]
I hate this house! It's too small!
I don't want to live in this hellhole!
Mark my words,
I'll return to that mansion!
Mark my words!
My shoes!
I hate this!
[exhales]
[somber music playing]
[house help] Good evening, sir.
Ma'am.
[Carlotta] Yes?
Diego.
Miss Carlotta, good evening.
Can I talk to Ivy?
I'm afraid she isn't here.
Where did she go?
I don't know. I couldn't reach her either.
Miss Carlotta, I'm begging you.
Please, let me talk to Ivy.
About what, Diego?
Ivy's been keeping a secret from me.
-Secret?
-Ms. Carlotta, what do you know?
What do you know about Ivy and Lily?
[suspenseful music plays]
Lily?
I-- I don't know. Who's Lily?
What are you talking about,
Diego? Just leave.
-Miss Carlotta, please…
-You should leave.
I have other matters to attend to, okay?
[Diego] You don't have to lie anymore.
I already know who Ivy really is.
[tense music playing]
I'll go now, Miss Carlotta. Thank you.
[exhales]
[foreboding music playing]
[Ivy] Mom, it's me.
Mom, it's me, your daughter.
Mom, it's me, Lily.
[Camia] Lily?!
Dear!
[Dante] Lily?
[young Lily] Mom?
Mom?
[suspenseful music playing]
[Dante] Lily, are you all right there?
[Lily] I'm fine, Dad.
This place looks great!
[suspenseful music playing]
[suspenseful music continues playing]
[breathing heavily]
-Mom? What happened to you?
-Lily, run…
-Shush!
-[Tonio] Hey!
Lily… Run!
[Lily] Mom!
[breathing heavily]
[voice shaking] Lily…
Lily…
Lily! [sobs]
[sobbing] Lily!
-Lily…
-Mom?
Lily…
Yes, Mom, that's me.
Do you remember me now?
-[sobbing]
-Do you remember me, Mom?
Do you remember me now?
Yes, it's me. I'm Lily!
[Camia sobbing]
["Wildflower" by Arnel Pineda playing]
♪ Let the rain ♪
♪ Fall down upon her ♪
♪ She's a free and gentle flower
Growing wild ♪
♪ Let her cry ♪
♪ For she's a lady ♪
♪ Let her dream… ♪
I won't rest until I've spoken to Ivy.
I want to hear the truth
straight from her.
[Loring] I think she's up to
something against your family.
Why would I look for Ivy?
I don't need anything from her.
[Arnaldo] Be sure of that. If I
learn you're betraying us again,
I'll forget you're my brother.
Right now, we only have each other.
Just you and me.
Where is Miss Aguas,
and what do you know about her?
Answer me!
[Emilia] You're going
to your mistress again?
Go on, do it. I'll burn her to ashes!
Good job. [laughing maniacally]
[theme music playing]